<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gary Wong&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://garywong.pro/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gary Wong&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://garywong.pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stop Writing CLI — Start Validating Design</title>
      <link>https://garywong.pro/posts/stop-writing-cli-start-validating-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://garywong.pro/posts/stop-writing-cli-start-validating-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Stop Writing CLI&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://garywong.pro/posts/stop-writing-cli-start-validating-design/cli.avif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-project-that-triggered-this-post&#34;&gt;The Project That Triggered This Post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was assigned to a mid-scale network migration spanning three data centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture was straightforward but labor-intensive: dozens of VRFs, hundreds of point-to-point BGP sessions in a BGP fabric, and a VMware NSX overlay. Despite this modern setup, I was asked to manually write all of the configuration changes as CLI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coding over &lt;strong&gt;6,000 lines of CLI&lt;/strong&gt; that night, I paused to reflect:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking the Cisco Nexus 9000 TCAM: A Real-World Fix and iCAM Insights</title>
      <link>https://garywong.pro/posts/nexus9000-tcam-icam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://garywong.pro/posts/nexus9000-tcam-icam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent project, I had the opportunity to work with something “new” yet familiar. During a customer data center refresh project, one of the key tasks was upgrading their aging Nexus 5000 to the new Nexus 9000 series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model in play? &lt;strong&gt;N93360YC-FX2&lt;/strong&gt;, a powerhouse with enhanced capabilities — but with a few nuances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, porting over configurations from the N5K seemed straightforward.&lt;br&gt;
No FCoE, no zoning, no fancy storage integrations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating Cisco Device Upgrades with Ansible: A Playbook Journey</title>
      <link>https://garywong.pro/posts/automating-cisco-device-upgrades-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://garywong.pro/posts/automating-cisco-device-upgrades-ansible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As networks scale and new software updates become available, keeping Cisco devices up to date is crucial for maintaining optimal performance, security, and functionality. However, manually upgrading multiple devices can be time-consuming and prone to errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where &lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt; comes into play, allowing us to automate and streamline the entire upgrade process for Cisco IOS/IOS-XE devices. Over the past few weeks, I’ve been working on a series of Ansible playbooks to automate this task efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continue the Network Automation Journey Using AWX</title>
      <link>https://garywong.pro/posts/awx-network-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://garywong.pro/posts/awx-network-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on a project recently to assist a customer in upgrading &lt;strong&gt;thousands of devices&lt;/strong&gt; in their network. Managing such a large-scale upgrade requires automation to ensure consistency, efficiency, and reduced manual intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project, &lt;strong&gt;AWX&lt;/strong&gt; was selected as the automation UI platform, providing a powerful interface for managing Ansible playbooks, job templates, inventories, and credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-awx&#34;&gt;What is AWX?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWX&lt;/strong&gt; is the upstream open-source project for Red Hat Ansible Tower.&lt;br&gt;
It provides an intuitive web UI for:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Digital and Traditional: My Journey in IT and Music</title>
      <link>https://garywong.pro/posts/navigating-digital-traditional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://garywong.pro/posts/navigating-digital-traditional/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! I’m Gary Wong, and I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to share with you my experiences and insights from a career that intertwines the rapidly evolving world of Information Technology with the timeless melodies of ancient Chinese music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-glimpse-into-my-professional-world&#34;&gt;A Glimpse into My Professional World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Senior Network Architect, my journey through the realms of IT has been both challenging and rewarding. With over 23 years in the industry, I&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed firsthand the incredible evolution of technology. My expertise spans a diverse array of areas, including networking, cloud computing, data center management, and cybersecurity. These fields, though distinct, are interconnected in fascinating ways, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of exploring these interconnections throughout my career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
